# ATIKAH MOHAMAD

# DATA ANALYST

012 378 7841 • atikah.mohamad@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/atikahmd



# SUMMARY

With over 8 years of professional experience in the IT, e-commerce, and sign manufacturing sectors, I have gained diverse skills across multiple job functions. From my time as an IT Developer to my role as an Admin Executive, I have successfully collaborated with multiple departments to accomplish shared objectives. I enjoy organizing tasks and graphic design and consume personal development content in my spare time.

Driven by a passion for data and its potential to reveal valuable insights, I aspire to transition into a Data Analyst role. Through my experience with SQL and Microsoft Excel, and my proficiency with Tableau, I have developed a strong foundation in data analysis. I recently completed a course to further enhance my data analytics skills, and plan to expand my technical knowledge with Python.

# SKILLS

Data Cleaning and Exploration

SQL

Microsoft Excel, Google Sheets

Python (Beginner)

Visualization

Tableau

**Business Intelligence** 

SAP BusinessObjects

Universe Design Tool

Google Analytics

Google Tag Manager

# PUBLICATIONS

### JOURNAL ARTICLE (2016)

Comparative Study of **Examination Question** Classification Tools

 NLP, text mining, machine learning

### **CONFERENCE PAPER (2013)**

Dahlia: Online Formative Assessment for Theoretical Course

D3.js, PHP

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### IT EXECUTIVE

Bumi Jaya Advertising (Remote) | Aug 2020 - Present (Part-time)

- Create a worksheet using Google Sheets to track expenses and worker salary advances, resulting in decreased time to calculate monthly wages
- Conduct thorough reviews of invoices and payment transactions to ensure accuracy of expenditure report
- Develop a WordPress website for pharmaceutical consulting firm that consistently generates inquiries from prospective customers
- Conduct market research on competitors' offerings and make recommendations for value propositions from firm's customer perspective
- Configure analytics components on Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager

### **ADMIN & BUILDING EXECUTIVE**

BloomThis (Petaling Jaya) | Nov 2021 - Oct 2022

- Conducted inventory data collection of office supplies and reduced waste by performing monthly stock counts
- Analyzed usage of cleaning supplies and optimized purchase schedule to reduce delivery fee
- Partnered with Procurement team to create a forecast report for cleaning supplies
- Led engagement with food vendors to provide biweekly lunches for 70+ employees on a limited budget
- · Managed vendor appointments and contract renewals and ensured accurate monthly invoicing
- Proposed a diversion of cold storage room outlet, saving at least RM1400 on yearly maintenance cost

# **PROJECTS**

# SUPERSTORE DATA ANALYSIS

Technology: Tableau

Conducted an in-depth analysis of sales data and suggested multiple actionable solutions to improve performance.

Accompanying visualization can be found here on Tableau Public.



# MOBILE APP PROFITABILITY

Technology: Python

Conducted an analysis of mobile app data and recommended an app category that has the potential to yield profits. Findings are documented <u>here</u> on GitHub.



# EDUCATION

### MASTER OF SCIENCE IN IT

UiTM Shah Alam | CGPA 3.95 2014 - 2016

#### BAC, OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

UiTM Shah Alam | CGPA 3.85 2011 - 2013

## DIP. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

UiTM Jengka | CGPA 3.95 2008 - 2011

### **EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT TO THE CEO OFFICE**

BloomThis (Kuala Lumpur) | May 2021 - Oct 2021

- Screened resumes from job portals and organized candidate information in Notion for team review
- Coordinated with hiring managers and candidates to schedule virtual and inperson interviews
- Developed a Google Form to supplement phone reference checks and accelerate hiring process for shortlisted candidates
- Established a recruitment dashboard utilizing Google Sheets functions and pivot tables for weekly HR and management meetings

### **TECH DEVELOPER**

BloomThis (Kuala Lumpur) | Oct 2017 - Dec 2019

- Maintained reports for digital marketing KPI on Google Sheets
- Utilized Supermetrics to incorporate insights from multiple sales channels
- Achieved a 40% reduction in time spent creating product catalogs for Facebook and Google by utilizing Liquid programming elements
- Managed digital assets (100+ products) on Shopify e-commerce platform
- Participated in data clean-up initiatives and streamlined product launch workflow

### IT DEVELOPER

Hewlett Packard Enterprise (Cyberjaya) | Apr 2014 - Oct 2017

- Held technical lead role in high-profile projects oversaw a team of 3 members in configuration of application and database, collaborating with multiple global teams to meet strict deadlines
- Achieved a 50% reduction in human error for database updates by creating a reusable DML script template
- Utilized SQL and Microsoft Excel to identify and address data discrepancies
- Worked closely with business users to clean and migrate data for timely delivery
- Employed Linux command line to process data files from SAP system
- Collected user requirements for monthly credit master data updates and executed changes in database

### **CREDIT & COLLECTIONS INTERN**

Hewlett Packard (Cyberjaya) | Sep 2013 - Mar 2014

- Developed web-based reports using SAP BusinessObject software for collection managers
- Analyzed business requirement documents and translated them into technical requirement documents
- Integrated data from multiple databases to provide business users with a consolidated view of collection activities
- Optimized database table joins in Universe Design Tool to improve report loading speed
- Identified and resolved issues during System Integration Testing (SIT) and User Acceptance Testing (UAT), obtaining timely user sign-off